Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company records, 1903-1969 (bulk 1903-1927)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company records, 1903-1969 (bulk 1903-1927)
AZ 183
Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company (Ariz.)
The collection includes correspondence, minutes of meetings, tax forms, ledgers, day books, bills, financial records, labor reports, time cards, payroll records, and maps from the daily operations of the mines, railroad and store. Also present are news clippings about Twin Buttes, Arizona and photographs of the 1926, 1928, and 1938 school classes.
36 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL:http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
Mining operation in the Twin Buttes area, Pima County, Arizona, subsequently leased or owned by Bush-Baxter, Glance Mining Company, Midland Copper Company, San Xavier Extension Copper Company. In addition to its mines the company operated a boarding house, store, and railroad.
Organization
This collection is organized into nine series:
Series I: Administrative Papers and Correspondence, 1903-1969
Series II: Financial Records (part 1), 1904-1927
Series III: Store Records, 1905-1912
Series IV: Financial Records (part 2), 1903-1929
Series V: Mine Records, 1906-1926
Series VI: Time Cards and Books, 1906-1910
Series VII: Identification Cards and Pay Account Records, 1907-1913
Series VIII: Railroad Records, 1904-1964
Series IX: Miscellaneous Material, 1906-1926
Scope and Content Note
The collection includes correspondence, minutes of meetings, tax forms, ledgers, day books, bills, financial records, labor reports, time cards, payroll records, and maps from the daily operations of the mines, railroad and store. Also present are news clippings about Twin Buttes, Arizona and photographs of the 1926, 1928, and 1938 school classes.
Access Terms
Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company (Ariz.) -- Archives
Twin Buttes Railroad Company (Ariz.) -- Records and correspondence
Bush-Baxter (Firm) -- Records and correspondence
Glance Mining Company -- Records and correspondence
Midland Copper Company -- Records and correspondence
San Xavier Extension Copper Company
Copper mines and mining -- Arizona -- History -- Sources
Mineral industries -- Arizona -- Finance -- Sources
Railroad companies -- Arizona -- History -- Sources
Copper miners -- History -- Sources
Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona -- Pima County -- History -- Sources
Mining corporations -- Arizona -- Records and correspondence
Twin Buttes (Ariz.)
Correspondence
Ledgers
Payroll
Time Cards
Container List
- Series I: Administrative Papers and Correspondence, 1903-1927
  - Administrative Papers: Articles of Organization; Prospectus. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Administrative Papers: Board of Directors meeting minutes (see also box 6a). 1904-1905 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Administrative Papers: Federal Trade Commission reports. 1918 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Administrative Papers: Forms used by the firm (blank). (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Administrative Papers: Insurance. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Administrative Papers: Legal agreements and proposals. 1903, 1905-1906, 1908, 1913, 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Administrative Papers: "Life and Times at Twin Buttes." (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Includes photographs, notes, meal tickets, newspaper clippings, dance tickets and various miscellaneous items.
  - Administrative Papers: Mining deeds; notices of location (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Administrative Papers: Financial and administrative reports. 1906-1923 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Administrative Papers: School District papers. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Administrative Papers: Stockholders meetings, proxies, etc. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Administrative Papers: Timber reports. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Administrative Papers: Wage scales. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Administrative Papers: Water analysis. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence. 1904, 1906, January 1907-May 1908 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence. June 1908, September 1909 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence. October 1909-August 1912 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence. September 1912-April 1913 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence. May-July 1913, 1914-1927 (Box 6)
  - Minutes. 1928-1969 (Box 6a, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence: Taxes. 1922-1924 (Box 6a, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence. 1923-1929 (Box 6a, Folder 4-5)
- Series II: Financial Records (part 1), 1904-1927
  - Taxes, Forms and Miscellaneous Financial Papers, 1904-1927
    - Taxes: Federal, Glance Mining Company. 1922-1924 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Taxes: Federal, Midland Copper Company. 1918-1925 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Taxes: Federal, San Xavier Extension Copper Company. 1918-1927 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Taxes: State, Glance Mining Company. 1917-1918, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Taxes: State, Midland Copper Company. 1920-1923 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Taxes: State, San Xavier Extension Copper Company. 1919-1923 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Taxes: State, Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company. 1907-1911 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Financial Papers: Miscellaneous, fragments and work sheets. 1904-1926 (Box 7, Folder 8-14)
    - Unidentified record book. January-July 1906 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Ledgers and Cash Accounts, 1906-1918
    - Ledgers. 1906-1907 (Box 8)
      Includes ledgers from:
      July-September 1906
      October 1906
      October 1906-April 1907 (Butcher Shop)
    - Ledgers. 1906-1918 (Box 9)
      1906-1910
      May-June 1912
      July 1912-April 1913
      1916-1918 (San Xavier Extension Copper Company)
    - Cash Account. August 1906-February 1907 (Volume 10)
      An additional Cash Account Record for 1913 is in box 67.
- Series III: Store Records, 1905-1912
  - Store Day Books and Journal, 1905-1911
    - Store Day Book. August 20-December 22, 1910 (Volume 10)
    - Journal. April-December 1907 (Volume 11)
    - Store Day Book. November 26, 1910-February 14, 1911 (Volume 11)
    - Store Day Books. 1905-1907 (Box 12)
      Thirteen books with the following date ranges:
      May 12, 1905-February 1906
      February-March 1906
      March 10-30, 1906
      March 28-April 16, 1906
      April 17-May 5, 1906
      May-June 1906
      June 26 -August 7, 1906
      August 7-31, 1906
      September 1-30, 1906
      October 1-30, 1906
      October 30-December 2, 1906 (Boletos and railroad fares)
      September 3-December 8, 1906 (Boletos)
      November 17, 1906-March 13, 1907
    - Store Day Books. 1907-1910 (Box 13)
      Seven books with the following date ranges:
      April 5-June 22, 1907 (includes individual accounts)
      June 24-September 30, 1907
      May 25-October 9, 1907 (Butcher Shop)
      October 1907-April 1908 (includes individual accounts)
      May 1-August 31, 1908
      August-November 1909 (includes individual accounts)
      December 1909-May 1910 (includes individual accounts)
    - Store Day Books. 1910-1911 (Box 14)
      Six books with the following date ranges:
      June 6-September 27, 1910
      October 20, 1910-January 16, 1911
      June 1911
      February 14-June 4, 1911 ("Book #1")
      January 17-May 22, 1911 ("Book #2")
      March 8-July 8, 1911 ("Book #3")
  - Miscellaneous Store Papers, 1906-1912
    - Coupon Books. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Inventories. August 31, 1906, June 30, 1907, October 25, 1907 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      October inventory includes also materials in the assay office, mines, and buildings in Twin Buttes.
    - Invoice records. 1907, 1910-1911 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Order sheet. February-April, 1907 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Sales slips. (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Series IV: Financial Records (part 2), 1903-1929
  - Bills: Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company. 1903-1906 (Box 16)
  - Bills: Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company. 1907-July 1909 (Box 17)
  - Bills: Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company. August 1909-May 1910 (Box 18)
  - Bills: Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company. June 1910-December 1911 (Box 19)
  - Bills: Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company, Bush-Baxter and Glance Mining Company. January 1912-May 1917 (Box 20)
  - Bills: Glance Mining Company, Midland Copper Company and San Xavier Extension Copper Company. June 1917-June 1923 (Box 21)
  - Bills: Midland Copper Company. July 1923-August 1925 (Box 22)
  - Bills: Midland Copper Company. September 1925-December 1927 (Box 23)
  - Albert Steinfeld and Company Bills: Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company, Twin Buttes Railroad. 1904-1906 (Box 24)
  - Albert Steinfeld and Company Bills: Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company, Twin Buttes Railroad. 1906-1907 (Box 25)
  - Albert Steinfeld and Company Bills: Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company, Twin Buttes Railroad. 1908-1909 (Box 26)
  - Albert Steinfeld and Company Bills: Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company, Bush-Baxter and Glance Mining Company. 1910-1917 (Box 27)
  - Albert Steinfeld and Company Bills: Glance Mining Company, San Xavier Extension Copper Company and Midland Copper Company. 1918-1926 (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous Business Records, 1907-1917
    - Checks. (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Orders for merchandise. 1907-1908, 1910-1911 (Box 29, Folder 2-3)
    - Pay check register. 1916-1917 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Receipts. (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Time checks and stubs. (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Vouchers. (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Check stubs: Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company (12 books). 1908-1913 (Box 30)
    - Check stubs: Bush-Baxter (10 books). 1912, 1914, 1916 (Box 30)
    - Check stubs: Glance Mining Company (2 books). August 1916, April-May 1917 (Box 30)
    - Check stubs: Midland Copper Company (1 book). May 19, 1917-March 19, 1919 (Box 30)
    - Check stubs: Midland Copper Company (17 books). July 1919-November 1925 (Box 31)
    - Check stubs: San Xavier Extension Copper Company (1 book). January 1920-April 1921 (Box 31)
    - Deposit slips: Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company. 1906-1911 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Deposit slips: Twin Buttes Railroad. 1907-1920 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Deposit slips: San Xavier Extension Copper Company. 1916-1918 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Deposit slips: Bush-Baxter. May-August 1915 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Deposit slips: Glance Mining Company. 1918-1920 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Deposit slips: Midland Copper Company. 1918-1927 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Bank Statements: Twin Buttes Railroad. 1908 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Bank Statements: Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company. 1912-1913 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Bank statements: Bush-Baxter. 1914-1917 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Bank statements: Glance Mining Company. 1916-1921 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Bank statements: San Xavier Extension Copper Company. 1917, 1920, 1922-1923 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Bank statements: Midland Copper Company. 1917-1928 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Check stubs: Midland Copper Company (6 books). 1925-1928 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Voucher Records: Twin Buttes Railroad. December 1904-July 1906, January-August 1906 (Box 33, Folder 1-2)
    - Voucher Records: Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company. October 1904, December 1904, February-April 1905, January-July 1906, April -November 1907 (Box 33, Folder 3-4)
    - Voucher Records: Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company and Twin Buttes Railroad. December 1905-August 1906 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Voucher Records: San Xavier Extension Copper Company. 1916-1918 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Payrolls, 1904-1929
    - Payrolls: Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company. February-March 1904, May-July 1904, October 1904, December 1904 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Payrolls: Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company. January-July 1905 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Payrolls: Twin Buttes Railroad. January-February 1905, April-July 1905, September-November 1905 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Payrolls: Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company. January-February 1906 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Payrolls: Twin Buttes Railroad. January-February 1906, May 1906 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Payrolls: Twin Buttes Railroad. December 1907, January-December 1908 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Payrolls: Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company. May-December 1909 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Payrolls: Twin Buttes Railroad. January-October 1909 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Payrolls: Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company. January-December 1910 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Payrolls: Twin Buttes Railroad. January-December 1910 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Payrolls: Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company. January-March 1911 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Payrolls: Twin Buttes Railroad. January-March 1911 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Payrolls: Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company. February-April 1913, June 1913 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Payrolls: Glance Mining Company, Bush-Baxter, Railroad. December 1915, January-February 1916, May-December 1916 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Payrolls: Glance Mining Company, Bush-Baxter, Railroad (some parts incomplete). January-December 1917 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Payrolls: Glance Mining Company, Bush-Baxter, Railroad (some parts incomplete). January-December 1918 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Payrolls: Glance Mining Company, Bush-Baxter, Railroad. November 1923, 1925 (fragment) (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Payrolls: Midland Copper Company. March 1919, June-October 1919, December 1919, June 1920, October-November 1920 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Payrolls: San Xavier Extension Copper Company. October-December 1916, 1917, January 1918, November-December 1918, January 1919, January-October 1920, December 1929 (Box 35, Folder 6)
- Series V: Mine Records, 1906-1926
  - Mine Records: Assay reports. 1907, 1913-1920, 1922, 1924, 1926 (Box 36, Folder 1-6)
  - Mine Records: Lumber yard issue slips. 1906-1907 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Mine Records: Ore shipping reports. 1912-1913? (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Mine Records: Survey field notes. (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Mine Records: Work reports. 1906-1910, 1915, 1925-1926 (Box 37)
    Reports consist of notes of individual miners; some of these are on printed forms other are on scraps of paper.
  - Mine Records: Inventories of mine equipment (see also box 15). 1916-1918, 1920, 1926 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Mine Records: Daily Mine Tally Report. September-October 1916, September-October 1919 (Box 38, Folder 2-3)
  - Mine Records: Warehouse requisitions. 1916-1925 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Mine Records: Daily powder reports. (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Mine Records: Memos regarding powder, caps, and fuses. (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Mine Records: Stock record cards. (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Mine Records: Time cards, (Twin Buttes Mining and Smelting Company?) April 1913 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Mine Records: Time cards, (Midland Copper Company). 1924-1926 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Mine Records: Pay rate job sheet. (Box 38, Folder 10)
- Series VI: Time Cards and Books, 1906-1910
  - Time cards: Assay office. 1907-1909 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Time cards: Boarding house. 1907-1908 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Time cards: Bridge gang. 1907 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Time cards: Bunk house. 1909-1910 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Time cards: Butcher shop. 1906-1907 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Time cards: Camp. December 1906-November 1909 (Box 39, Folder 5-7)
  - Time cards: Center Group. 1908-1910 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Time cards: Copper Hill Mine. 1906-1908 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Time cards: Copper King Mine. 1906-1907 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Time cards: Copper Prince Mine. 1906-1908 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Time cards: Copper Glance Mine. 1907 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Time cards: Corral. 1907-1909 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Time cards: Kitchen. 1906-1907 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Time cards: Patenting Claims. 1908-1909 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Time cards: Senator Stewart Mine. 1906-1908 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Time cards: Twin Buttes Group. 1908 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Time cards: Various Groups. 1908 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Time cards: Store. 1906-1910 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Time cards: Teaming. 1907 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Time cards: Water System. 1908 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Time cards: Morgan Mine. 1906, January 1907 (Box 41)
  - Time cards: Morgan Mine. February-May 1907 (Box 42)
  - Time cards: Morgan Mine. May-December 1907 (Box 43)
  - Time cards: Morgan Mine. January-August 1908 (Box 44)
  - Time cards: Morgan Mine. September-December 1908 (Box 45)
  - Time cards: Morgan Mine. January-May 1909 (Box 46)
  - Time cards: Morgan Mine. June-December 1909 (Box 47)
  - Time cards: Morgan Mine. 1910 (Box 48)
  - Time cards: Office. 1906-1910 (Box 48)
  - Time cards: Railroad construction. 1906-1907 (Box 49)
  - Time cards: Railroad operating. 1907-1910 (Box 49)
  - Time cards: Railroad miscellaneous. 1906-1907 (Box 50)
  - Time cards: Railroad roundhouse. 1906-1907 (Box 50)
  - Time cards: Railroad train crew. 1906-1907 (Box 50)
  - Time cards: Railroad section 1. April 1907-March 1910 (Box 51)
  - Time cards: Railroad section 2. 1906-1910 (Box 52)
  - Time cards: Railroad section 3. 1906-1907 (Box 53)
  - Time cards: Railroad section 4. 1907 (Box 53)
  - Time cards: Railroad section 5. 1907 (Box 53)
  - Time Books: Annual assessment work (2 books). October-November 1908 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Time Books: Boarding House (2 books). November 1907-February 1908, August-September 1908 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Time Books: Corral. February-June 1908 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Time Books: Mine. February 1905-August 1906 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Time Books: Mine. September-December 1906 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Time Books: Morgan Mine (13 books). January-December 1908 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Time Books: Morgan Mine (20 books). January-December 1909 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Time Books: Morgan Mine (4 books). January-March 1910 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Time Books: Teams (2 books). June 1906, May 1907 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Time Books: Railroad. January-July 1906 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Time Books: Railroad section 1 (4 books). June-July 1906, November 1907-July 1908, January-June 1909, September-October 1910 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Time Books: Railroad section 2 (10 books). August-September 1908, December 1908, January-March 1909, May-July 1909, October 1909 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Time Books: Railroad section 3 (2 books). April 1907, September-November 1908 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Time Books: Railroad miscellaneous (15 books). 1906 (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - Time Books: Arizona Smelting and Refining Company. August 1915 (Box 54, Folder 13)
- Series VII: Identification Cards and Pay Account Records, 1907-1913
  - Identification Cards: Boarding house. 1907 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Identification Cards: Camp. 1907 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Identification Cards: Copper Glance Mine. 1907 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Identification Cards: Copper Hill Mine. 1907 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Identification Cards: Morgan Mine. 1907, 1910 (Box 55, Folder 5-7)
  - Identification Cards: Railroad sections 1, 2 and 4. 1907 (Box 55, Folder 8-10)
  - Pay Account Records. 1912-1913 (Box 56)
- Series VIII: Railroad Records, 1904-1964
  - Railroad Papers: Administrative Reports, Meetings, etc. 1904-1911 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Railroad Papers: Bridge construction. (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Railroad Papers: Miscellaneous financial papers. (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Railroad Papers: General Monthly Summary. March, May 1906, April-December 1907, January-May 1908 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Railroad Papers: Operating Department orders. 1905-1907 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Railroad Papers: Passes. 1909-1910 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Railroad Papers: Per diem reports. 1906-1910, 1913 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Railroad Papers: Right of Way papers. 1910, 1916 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Railroad Papers: Tax Returns. 1908-1909, 1923-1926 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Railroad Papers: Trial balance. 1907-1910 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Murphy, James J. "Twin Buttes Railroad." Arizonian, v. 5, nos. 1-2. 1964 (Box 57)
  - Railroad Papers: Audits. 1909-1910 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Railroad Papers: Claims. 1907-1909 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Railroad Papers: Locomotive repair reports. 1906, 1925-1926 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Railroad Papers: Miscellaneous receipts. (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Railroad Papers: Requisitions and stubs. 1906 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Railroad Papers: Signs, tags, forms, regulations. (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Railroad Papers: Reports to Interstate Commerce Commission. 1908-1909, 1911 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Railroad Papers: Tariff tables. (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Railroad Papers: Time checks and stubs. 1905-1907 (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Railroad Papers: Vouchers. (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Railroad Papers: Baggage checks. (Box 59)
    On original wire, hung in the Twin Buttes Depot.
  - Railroad Papers: Grade survey, Tucson to Twin Buttes. (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Railroad Papers: Distribution of track labor. 1907-1911 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Railroad Papers: Report of Train Operation. January-February, 1913, May 1913 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Railroad Papers: Miscellaneous shipping reports. 1906-1926 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Railroad Papers: U.S. Mail Records. 1908-1910 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Railroad Papers: Work Train Service for the Southern Pacific Company. July 1909-March 1910 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Railroad Papers: Southern Pacific Company tariff rates, rules and regulations, etc. 1908-1912 (Box 60, Folder 1-2)
  - Railroad Papers: Bills of lading, shipping orders. (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Railroad Papers: Freight bills. 1906-1908 (Box 60, Folder 4-6)
  - Railroad Papers: Freight bills. 1909 (Box 61)
  - Freight Conductor's Train Book (3 books). April-August 1907, January-May 1910 (Box 61)
  - Railroad Papers: Record of Freight Bills. April-June 1907 (Volume 62)
  - Railroad Papers: Conductor's daily report. 1906-1907, 1911 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Railroad Papers: Section Foreman's daily report, Sections 1-4. 1906-1907 (Box 62, Folder 2-3)
  - Railroad Papers: Waybills. (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Railroad Papers: Abstract of Interline Waybills (Southern Pacific to Twin Buttes Railroad). 1910-1911 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Railroad Papers: Abstract of Interline Waybills (Twin Buttes Railroad to Southern Pacific). 1910-1911 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Railroad Papers: Souther Pacific Company Interline Waybill correction notice and accounts. September-December 1910, January-September 1911, December 1911 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Railroad Papers: Agent's daily ticket report (Tucson and Twin Buttes stations). 1906 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Railroad Papers: Agent's daily ticket report, daily balance sheet, daily abstract (Tucson and Twin Buttes stations). 1907 (Box 64, Folder 6-10)
  - Railroad Papers: Agent's daily ticket report, daily balance sheet, daily abstract (Tucson and Twin Buttes stations). 1908 (Box 65, Folder 1-6)
  - Railroad Papers: Agent's daily ticket report, daily balance sheet, daily abstract (Tucson station). 1909 (Box 65, Folder 7-8)
- Series IX: Miscellaneous Material, 1906-1926
  - Catalogs of Mine and Railroad Equipment. (Box 66)
  - Cash Book Records. February-June 1913 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Daily Supply Distribution Sheet. July-September 1907 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Explosives (Glance Mine, Queen Mine). 1918 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Monthly Supply Distribution Sheet. February 1918, April-December 1918 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Ore Shipments. 1912-1913, 1917-1918, 1925-1926 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Revenue Derived from Copper. August-December 1918, January 1919 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Section Foreman's Inventory of Materials and Tools on Hand accompanied by Storekeeper's Inventory Work Sheets. June-November 1907, July 1908, March 1909 (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Daily Segregation of Labor (Minnie Mine, Glance Mine). No Date (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Summary of Labor Segregation. April-May 1917, December 1923, 1924, October 1925, January-June 1926, August 1926 (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Signs, poster, certificate, etc. (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - Maps. (Box 67, Folder 11)
    Includes:
    Relocation of railroad
    Right of Way for highway through mining claims, 1920